A love story so unusual it has to be true.
Carrington is a history, drama, romance film directed by Christopher Hampton.
Painter Dora Carrington develops an intimate but extremely
complex bond with writer Lytton Strachey.
Though Lytton is a homosexual, he is enchanted by the mysterious Dora and they
begin a lifelong friendship that has strangely romantic undertones.
Eventually, Lytton and Dora decide to live together, despite the fact that the latter has
fallen in love with military man Ralph Partridge, whom she plans to marry.
Dora Carrington, played by Emma Thompson.
Lytton Strachey, played by Jonathan Pryce.
Ralph Partridge, played by Steven Waddington.
Gerald Brenan, played by Samuel West.
Mark Gertler, played by Rufus Sewell.
Lady Ottoline Morrell, played by Penelope Wilton.
Carrington is a 1995 British biographical film written and directed by Christopher Hampton about the life
of the English painter Dora Carrington (1893–1932), who was known simply as "Carrington".
The screenplay is based on Lytton Strachey: A Critical Biography, the 1967–68 two-volume
biography of writer and critic Lytton Strachey (1880–1932) by Michael Holroyd.
The film explores themes of england, painter,
conscientious objector, soldier, polyamory.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.